<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Agathis Project – Agathis Project</title>
    <link>https://agathisproject.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Agathis Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://agathisproject.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: On Project Names</title>
      <link>https://agathisproject.github.io/blog/2020/05/02/on-project-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://agathisproject.github.io/blog/2020/05/02/on-project-names/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The work around here is organized in projects, each one with its own repository; they &lt;strong&gt;must&lt;/strong&gt; be uniquely identified.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the description of the project as its name is a horrible idea.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The project names must have some level of consistency; numbers, or other random codes are out of the question.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choosing a project name should be an easy task - as easy as pick one from a list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Need a pool of project names lager than 1000.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I like trees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-decided&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I decided:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-the-projects-shall-be-named-from-the-list-of-practical-unlimited-supply-provided-by-the-list-of-trees-and-shrubs-by-taxonomic-familyhttpsenwikipediaorgwikilist_of_trees_and_shrubs_by_taxonomic_family-the-list-is-1351-long-plenty-to-choose-from&#34;&gt;1. The projects &lt;strong&gt;shall&lt;/strong&gt; be named from the list of practical unlimited supply provided by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_trees_and_shrubs_by_taxonomic_family&#34;&gt;List of trees and shrubs by taxonomic family&lt;/a&gt;. The list is 1351 long, plenty to choose from.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-the-repository-name-shall-be-same-as-the-project-name&#34;&gt;2. The repository name &lt;strong&gt;shall&lt;/strong&gt; be same as the project name.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;3-the-name-shall--use-the-latin-variant-with-a-hyphen-as-in-juniperus-ashey&#34;&gt;3. The name &lt;strong&gt;shall&lt;/strong&gt;  use the latin variant with a hyphen as in &lt;em&gt;juniperus-ashey&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;4-no-tree-is-above-others---in-other-words-bigger-is-not-better-distinctive-or-more-different-is&#34;&gt;4. No tree is above others - in other words, bigger is not better. Distinctive or more different is.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;5-look-at-the-names-already-in-use-choose-a-good-one-and-easy-to-remember-name-or-ask-for-help&#34;&gt;5. Look at the names already in use, choose a good one and easy to remember name, or ask for help.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;6-each-project-name-goes-through-one-month-trial-period---if-something-soundslooksfeels-out-of-place-about-the-name-then-pick-another-name-anyone-can-share-their-opinion-but-i-will-take-the-final-decision&#34;&gt;6. Each project name goes through one month trial period - if something sounds/looks/feels out of place about the name, then pick another name. Anyone can share their opinion, but I will take the final decision.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;7-some-project-names-need-to-be-supported-with-a-short-descriptive-name-until-they-grow-stronger-and-get-a-general-recognition-on-their-own-ex-ficus-elastica-workflow&#34;&gt;7. Some project names need to be supported with a short descriptive name until they grow stronger and get a general recognition on their own (ex: ficus-elastica workflow)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;8-until-a-more-suitable-process-is-introduced-i-will-rule-and-take-responsibility-on-any-issues-related-to-project-naming&#34;&gt;8. Until a more suitable process is introduced, I will rule and take responsibility on any issues related to project naming.&lt;/h4&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: website is up</title>
      <link>https://agathisproject.github.io/blog/2020/04/22/website-is-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://agathisproject.github.io/blog/2020/04/22/website-is-up/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Today, the Agathis Project website was published for the first time; it&amp;rsquo;s only a newborn - its structure looks ok for now and ready to grow.
It&amp;rsquo;s not walking yet, but that&amp;rsquo;s fine too. It&amp;rsquo;s learning, mostly from my mistakes. There will be many. I don&amp;rsquo;t see the shortcuts yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The website is designed to &lt;strong&gt;introduce the Agathis Project&lt;/strong&gt; to all its prospective collaborators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;labor&lt;/strong&gt; part in the &lt;strong&gt;collaborators&lt;/strong&gt; is essential, although not limiting to building machines and tools, hardware or software. The collaboration may come in many other forms, such as using the said machines, sharing an idea on how to make them better, spreading the word, feedback of any sign, or any kind of neural activity triggered while navigating the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you are already in, the website can be used as periodical reality check, an alignment tool or a compass to verify the directions are right.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The site is build using open-source &lt;strong&gt;Hugo&lt;/strong&gt; site generator with a &lt;strong&gt;Docsy&lt;/strong&gt; template.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
