<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Agathis Project – projects</title>
    <link>https://agathisproject.github.io/docs/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in projects on Agathis Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://agathisproject.github.io/docs/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: system specs</title>
      <link>https://agathisproject.github.io/docs/projects/system_specs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://agathisproject.github.io/docs/projects/system_specs/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;!--


&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;see repository pinus-rigida&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Agathis Tree is an open source IT modules stack designed ground-up for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;structural robustness, ingress protection, high cooling capacity and electromagnetic immunity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;optimized data connectivity for performance, growing ecosystems and scalable power delivery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each module is provided with its own built-in shell enclosure solving a critical point in system scalability,  design and production costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system grows only when needed as modules are added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By clamping the printed circuit cards on their four edges, the shell enclosure eliminate mechanical resonances normally experienced by other systems, making the Agathis structure most suitable to operate in high shock and vibration environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the size of the electronic systems decreases and space between devices is getting smaller and smaller, convection cooling is no longer an effective option. The Agathis tree is designed from the ground-up for cost optimized conduction/liquid cooling through coordinated use of standardized shells, PCBs and optional liquid cooling or heat-pipes for efficient heat extraction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While reducing the operating temperature in a system is the primary way to increase its reliability, thermal balancing is just as relevant in reducing mechanical stress, fatigue and early component failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Agathis modules use their shells as high capacity built-in heat transfer devices to maintain a uniform temperature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electromagnetic compatibility (EMC) and EM immunity against high energy electromagnetic pulses (EMP) is a high concern in any electronic system design. Agathis addresses these issues 
by using the module’s shell for inter-module shielding and shielding against external aggressors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Agathis standard supports low cost lab, production and field testing tools. A production tester, designed as an Agathis module, can be easily adapted to operate as a field tester module for lower costs and improved coverage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A JTAG chain supports in-field testing and logic reprogramming. The FPGA devices are critical for Agathis ecosystem flexibility and diversity and they are supported for intra-system in-field testing and reprogramming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The power delivery uses load sharing technology over 5V power rail with 100A capability for maximum of 500W for the entire stack. Load sharing technology reduces electrical and thermal stress and increase system reliability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Module Management Controller (MMC), a dedicated firmware module active in every management microcontroller (MC) manages the power and hardware configuration on every module.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tree Management Controller (TMC), a dedicated firmware module active in the designated management microcontroller (MC) can supervise up to 16 module.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clock distribution in multi-point configuration supports data communication clock (100MHz) and instrumentation clock (10MHz).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Precision timing distribution delivers multi-point 1PPS trigger to the entire tree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Industry standard module to module interfaces:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2x USB2.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 x1 PCIe3.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;x16 PCIe4.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agathis specific multi-point interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BLVDS source synchronous serial interface (clock and data).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
